Sean Thomas Canavan

TECHNICAL DIRECTOR & SOFTWARE ARCHITECT

CONTACT



512 - 806 - 8287



seantcanavan@gmail.com



/in/seantcanavan



Tulsa, OK

EDUCATION

B.S. SOFTWARE ENGINEERING San Jose State University 2009-2013

> MINOR: MATHEMATICS San Jose State University 2006-2009

EXPERTISE

Getting up to speed quickly

Learning new languages on the fly

Quality, tested code

Cross-team collaboration

Strong processes and documentation

AWS/Google Cloud infrastructure

Automate everything

Debugging and Root Cause Analysis

Project timelines & estimation

Performance and Complexity Analysis

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

A technical director and software architect with over 12 years of programming experience and a proven track record leading local, remote, and overseas teams cohesively. Blending a strong set of written and verbal communication skills with a rock-solid programming and systems design mindset to build world-class products in highly collaborative and agile environments.

EXPERIENCE

TECHNICAL DIRECTOR & SOFTWARE ARCHITECT GitWit, LLC

2021 - 2022

Principal software architect in charge of rewriting a tech-debt ridden codebase to a full MEAN stack project including database migration. Launched in just six months without bugs while mastering MEAN stack and Google Cloud.

- Automate \$2mil/year COVID child-care benefits for essential workers
- Design and allocate database, server, and front-end infrastructure
- Automate builds and deployments to allow for rapid releases (CI/CD)
- Increase speed of change deployment from days to minutes
- Author technical documentation and mentor fellow engineers

TECH LEAD & FULL STACK DEVELOPER GoGuardian

2018 - 2021

Technical lead for the GoGuardian Admin product's engineering teams both local and overseas. Lead design discussions, cross-team collaborations, and act as the first point of contact for all technical questions related to the product. Perform feasibility analysis and story point estimation for all significant engineering initiatives.

- Successfully migrate a team to full remote work in response to COVID
- Integrate a fully remote team of engineers effectively doubling the team's code output while also raising the NPS score 20 points
- Spearhead process improvement across multiple critical areas including merging, deploying, code review, and code quality
- Principle engineer in charge of hiring, maintaining the engineering culture, and mentoring and teaching interns and new hires
- Designed and scaled a modern web app and microservice infrastructure including a full UI redesign using React/Node/GoLang

Sean Thomas Canavan

TECHNICAL DIRECTOR & SOFTWARE ARCHITECT

SKILLS

TECHNICAL

Systems design and code reviews
Serverless architecture
Modern web app design patterns
MySQL vs NoSQL
Server and database architecture

INTERPERSONAL

Verbal and written communication
Team leadership and motivation
Safeguarding company culture
Hiring, internships, mentoring

LANGUAGES

NestJS

TypeScript / NodeJS

GoLang / Java / Python

React / Angular

INTERESTS

Gaming / Virtual Reality

NAS / Linux / Servers

Computer Hardware

Top 4% Stack Overflow Contributor

GitHub & Open Source Contributor

EXPERIENCE (Continued)

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Repost Network

2017 - 2018

Second engineer at a burgeoning tech music startup focusing on digital rights management and music distribution for new and upcoming artists. Work directly with the CTO daily and help the company grow their userbase 3x, become head of company culture, and perform pivotal hiring duties.

- Lead architect and developer for six microservices all deployed to AWS Lambda including a robust user login service supporting 2FA
- Successfully migrate an acquired startup's software stack from a local on-prem deployment to AWS RDS & EBS with zero downtime
- Host database design and systems architecture meetings for all new microservices
- Self-teach Spring Boot and Java EE on the job as well as limitless scaling via AWS DynamoDB and Lambda serverless architecture

CLOUD SECURITY ENGINEER Cisco Systems

2016 - 2017

Support Cisco's private cloud initiative by developing on-prem device tools for managing customers' proprietary software.

- Self-teach GoLang and Git and quickly rise to become a senior advocate for both technologies within the development team
- Utilize complex multi-threaded locks, channels, and go routines to asynchronously manage external processes and their log output
- Build a secure data pipeline using public / private key certificates to transmit logging data to the cloud for analysis and storage

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, CONTRACTOR YouTube, LLC

2014 - 2015

Develop automation, data ingestion, and data correction infrastructure for Google Play / YouTube Movie and TV content teams.

- Principal developer for an external client-facing Java web app that validates millions of lines of incoming Google Play Movies metadata
- Utilize the YouTube API to correct common metadata errors

Sean Thomas Canavan

TECHNICAL DIRECTOR & SOFTWARE ARCHITECT

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

EFFECTIVE COMMUNICATION
SKILLS
Effective Training Solutions
2016

CISCO SECURITY NINJA, WHITE
BELT
Cisco Systems
2016

CISCO SECURITY NINJA, GREEN
BELT
Cisco Systems
2016

EXPERIENCE (Continued)

HARDWARE ENGINEER - INTERN JDSUniphase

2012 - 2013

Design and build high quality testing tools for hardware engineers to see data flowing across hardware buses in real time.

- Lead developer for an eight-month C# project starting from initial requirements elicitation and software architecture design all the way to release, feature requests, and support
- Display memory maps for embedded devices asynchronously across multiple unique GUI views in real time via the MVC software design pattern and Windows Presentation Foundation

HARDWARE ENGINEER - INTERN SanDisk formerly Pliant

2010 - 2012

Perform physical testing of bleeding edge enterprise solid state hard drives and create instant value by freeing up senior engineering resources. Rapidly move into firmware testing automation and test data infrastructure design.

- Design custom automated test suites for enterprise SSD devices to measure power and performance simultaneously over time using Java, Python, and MATLAB
- Implement python log scraping and uploading utility to transmit log data to a SQL Server database empowering analytics tools

REFERENCES

KAITLYN NOONE Software Engineer | GitWit 785-543-7484 PETER JESSEE Software Engineer | GitWit 918-630-0035